[tires squealing]
[轮胎吱吱声]
[engine revs]
[发动机转速]
Now, SpongeBob,
现在，海绵宝宝，
what is the proper procedure
for making a right turn?
正确的程序是什么
为了右转？
Hmm...
唔...
Ooh!
哦！
Hold on,
I'll check the textbook.
坚持住，
我去查一下课本。
[shouts]
[喊叫]
Ah, your mirror and you.
啊，你的镜子和你。
No.
不。
Oh, proper seatbelt hygiene?
哦，正确的安全带卫生？
No.
不。
Assuming crash position.
假设碰撞位置。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇哇哇！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[surf rock music]
[冲浪摇滚音乐]
[screaming and tires squealing]
[尖叫声和轮胎尖叫声]
[yowls]
[嚎叫]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[brakes screeching]
[刹车声]
[gasps]
We didn't crash!
[喘气]
我们没有坠毁！
Hooray!
万岁！
♪ ♪
♪♪
both: Huh?
两人：啊？
[crashing and banging]
[碰撞和撞击]
[bones shaking]
[骨头颤抖]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Mrs. Puff?
泡芙夫人？
Oh, there you are!
哦，你在那里！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Oh!
哦！
[strains]
[菌株]
[giggles nervously]
[紧张地咯咯笑]
I'll make it up to you,
Mrs. Puff!
我会补偿你的
泡芙太太！
- Oh!
- Shine your shoes?
- 哦！
- 擦鞋吗？
[tongue squeaks]
[舌头吱吱作响]
Style your hair?
设计你的头发？
[hair dryer whirs]
[吹风机呼呼地响]
Ow!
噢！
[groans angrily]
[愤怒地呻吟]
Oil your boat?
给你的船加油吗？
Oh, ah!
哦，啊！
[gasps]
[喘气]
Spongebob... [stammers]
海绵宝宝……[结巴]
stop!
停止！
Cease!
And desist!
并停止！
[breathes heavily]
[呼吸粗重]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Well, you could
clean up all this junk.
嗯，你可以
清理所有这些垃圾。
I've been tossing stuff in this
old lighthouse for 20 years.
我一直在里面扔东西
老灯塔已经有20年历史了。
Ooh!
哦！
I love cleaning!
我爱清洁！
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Glad to hear it.
很高兴听到这个消息。
I'll be in my classroom.
我会在我的教室里。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Oh!
哦！
And if you need me...
如果你需要我...
don't.
不。
[inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
[meditative music plays]
[冥想音乐响起]
[heavy metal music plays]
[重金属音乐响起]
♪ Talk to the fin! ♪
♪ 与鳍交谈！ ♪
♪ Don't care
where you've been! ♪
♪ 不在乎
你去过哪里！ ♪
♪ ♪
[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
[shouts excitedly]
[兴奋地喊道]
[grunts and strains]
[咕哝声和压力]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[squeaks like a dolphin]
[像海豚一样吱吱叫]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[alarm rings]
[警报响起]
[drum thumps]
[击鼓声]
[strains]
[菌株]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[jabbers excitedly]
[兴奋地叽叽喳喳]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[gobbles]
[狼吞虎咽]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[burps]
[打嗝]
[knuckles crack]
[指关节断裂]
[grunts theatrically]
[戏剧性地咕哝]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[jabbers excitedly]
[兴奋地叽叽喳喳]
Ah, that takes care of that.
啊，这就解决了。
Huh?
Hmm.
啊？
唔。
♪ ♪
♪♪
[coughs]
[咳嗽]
Yuck, this place
needs a good scrub.
恶心，这个地方
需要好好擦洗。
♪ ♪
♪♪
[slurps]
[啜饮]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Oh, whoa, whoa!
哦，哇哦！
Whoa!
哇！
Ah!
Almost done.
啊!
快完成了。
I just need to shine up
the old lighthouse's lantern.
我只需要闪耀
老灯塔的灯笼。
[eerie howl]
[怪异的嚎叫]
[gasps]
[喘气]
The lighthouse is haunted!
灯塔闹鬼了！
Just like my toaster.
就像我的烤面包机一样。
[ghostly howls]
[幽灵般的嚎叫]
[wails loudly]
[大声哀嚎]
Um...
嗯...
[door squeaks]
[门吱吱作响]
[horror movie music]
[恐怖电影音乐]
Whoa!
哇！
That box is haunted!
那个盒子闹鬼了！
[grunts and groans]
[咕哝和呻吟]
These stairs are haunted!
这些楼梯闹鬼！
♪ ♪
♪♪
[shouts]
[喊叫]
♪ ♪
♪♪
This trash is haunted.
这个垃圾是闹鬼的。
[growls]
[咆哮]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[growls]
[咆哮]
[intense dramatic music]
[激烈的戏剧音乐]
[meows]
[喵喵]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Ghost snail!
幽灵蜗牛！
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- [meows]
- Hmm?
- [喵]
- 嗯？
Oh!
[giggles]
哦！
[咯咯笑]
You're no ghost!
你不是鬼！
Just a cute little stray snail!
简直就是一只可爱的小蜗牛啊！
How about I call you Louie?
我叫你路易怎么样？
- [purrs]
- Lighthouse Louie!
- [呼噜声]
- 灯塔路易！
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Meow, meow!
喵喵！
[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
Now Louie, you be good
while Uncle SpongeBob cleans.
路易，你要乖一点
当海绵宝宝叔叔打扫卫生时。
[strains]
[菌株]
[meows]
[喵喵]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Oy, oy!
哎哟，哎哟！
Oh.
哦。
♪ ♪
♪♪
[meows]
[喵喵]
Louie, I'm afraid you'll have
to play out here, little fella,
路易，恐怕你会
来这里玩，小家伙，
for your own safety.
为了您自己的安全。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Phew!
唷！
[hair dryer whirs]
[吹风机呼呼地响]
[coach's whistle blows]
[教练哨声响起]
[telephone rings]
[电话铃声]
[meows]
[喵喵]
- - What?
- Louie?
- - 什么？
- 路易？
[upbeat Hawaiian music]
[欢快的夏威夷音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Well, that oughta keep you
out of my
好吧，那应该让你
从我的
hair?
头发？
[meows]
[喵喵]
Sorry, Louie.
对不起，路易。
You have to stay outside.
你必须呆在外面。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ow!
噢！
[metallic clang]
[金属铿锵声]
No silly little snail
没有愚蠢的小蜗牛
is a match for
my superior sponge brain!
是一个匹配项
我优越的海绵大脑！
[wails]
[哀号]
[plops]
[扑通扑通]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[giggles quietly]
[轻声笑]
[can opener whirs]
[开罐器呼呼地响]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
And the bait, one can o' patty!
还有诱饵，一罐肉饼！
[chuckles confidently]
[自信地笑]
[meows excitedly]
[兴奋喵]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[slurping]
[发出声音]
Gotcha!
明白了！
[meows]
[喵喵]
I don't gotcha?
我不明白吗？
You got me.
你有我。
[straining]
[紧张]
[blabbers]
[喋喋不休]
Barnacles, that's heavy!
藤壶，好重啊！
Huh?
啊？
Ah!
啊!
[suspenseful ukulele music]
[悬疑的尤克里里音乐]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
[old-timey sailor music]
[老式水手音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Huh?
啊？
Where'd Louie go?
路易去哪儿了？
[balloon squeaks]
[气球吱吱声]
Louie, Louie!
路易，路易！
Louie!
路易！
[meows]
[喵喵]
Louie!
路易！
So this is where
you've been hiding!
所以这就是地方
你一直躲着！
[snarls ferociously]
[凶猛地咆哮]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
Nice snail.
Good Louie!
好蜗牛。
好路易！
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[yelping and snarling]
[尖叫和咆哮]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Whoa!
哇！
Those dudes are huge!
那些家伙太伟大了！
I wonder what they lift!
我想知道他们举起的是什么！
[gasps]
[喘气]
Those aren't dudes.
那些不是家伙。
They're giant monsters!
他们是巨型怪物！
Everybody panic!
大家都慌了！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[crunching and yelling]
[嘎吱嘎吱的声音]
[lighthouse rumbles and creaks]
[灯塔的隆隆声和吱吱声]
[growling]
[咆哮]
[screaming and angry meowing]
[尖叫和愤怒的喵喵声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
Those buff monsters
have vanished!
那些buff怪物
消失了！
We're saved!
我们得救了！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[screaming and angry meowing]
[尖叫和愤怒的喵喵声]
We're doomed!
我们注定了！
[slurps]
[啜饮]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[straw slurping]
[吸管的声音]
Oof!
钱币！
[gasps]
[喘气]
My cheeks!
我的脸颊！
[news station theme music]
[新闻台主题音乐]
Can you please tell our viewers
您能告诉我们的观众吗
the cause of this destruction?
造成这种破坏的原因是什么？
It was a lighthouse!
那是一座灯塔！
It rolled through town,
它滚过城镇，
destroying everything in its path!
摧毁其路径上的一切！
[hyperventilates]
[换气过度]
A lighthouse!
灯塔！
[bawls]
[大哭]
My goodness.
天哪。
Were you or
你是
your legs
你的腿
injured by this insane lighthouse?
被这座疯狂的灯塔伤害了？
No.
没有。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[high-pitched scream]
[高声尖叫]
That blasted lighthouse is
gonna demolish me Krusty Krab!
那个被毁的灯塔是
要把我毁掉蟹堡王！
Attention, loyal customers!
忠实顾客请注意！
Run for our lives?
为我们的生命而逃？
No, throw your bodies
in front of that lighthouse
不，扔你的身体
在那座灯塔前面
and protect me restaurant!
并保护我餐厅！
[building rattles]
[建筑嘎嘎声]
[screaming and panic]
[尖叫和恐慌]
[screaming and angry meowing]
[尖叫和愤怒的喵喵声]
No, not the Krusty Krab!
不，不是蟹堡王！
Stay away from me restaurant,
离我远点的餐厅，
you dirty, uh, lighthouse!
你这个肮脏的灯塔！
[screaming and angry meowing]
[尖叫和愤怒的喵喵声]
[high-pitched scream]
[高声尖叫]
Must... stop... lighthouse!
必须...停止...灯塔！
[meows]
[喵喵]
[cries out]
[喊叫]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[bones shaking]
[骨头颤抖]
Huh?
啊？
[laughs]
[笑]
And don't come back!
并且不要回来！
[laughs]
[笑]
[dramatic ukulele music]
[戏剧性的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[moans]
[呻吟声]
You came back.
你回来了。
[screaming and angry meowing]
[尖叫和愤怒的喵喵声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ow!
噢！
[heavy metal music plays]
[重金属音乐响起]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
[wheels squeaking]
[车轮吱吱作响]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
Louie?
路易？
Where's Louie?
路易在哪儿？
[meows]
[喵喵]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[purrs]
[呼噜声]
[happy meowing and purring]
[快乐的喵喵声和呼噜声]
[peaceful music]
[平静的音乐]
Aww, Louie!
哇，路易！
You weren't trying
to stop me from cleaning!
你没有尝试
阻止我打扫卫生！
You were just protecting
your cute little babies.
你只是在保护
你们可爱的小宝贝们。
together: [meows]
一起：[喵]
I guess I should call you
Louise instead.
我想我应该给你打电话
取而代之的是路易丝。
[laughs]
[笑]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[gasps]
[喘气]
You actually did a good job,
SpongeBob!
其实你已经做得很好了
海绵宝宝！
You deserve a gold star!
你值得一颗金星！
[squeals]
Gold star!
[尖叫声]
金星！
I have a present for you too,
Mrs. Puff!
我也给你准备了一份礼物
泡芙太太！
[purring and meowing]
[咕噜声和喵喵声]
And these little cuties were
hiding in your lighthouse.
这些小可爱们是
躲在你的灯塔里。
Oh![laughs]
哦！[笑]
Aren't you adorable!
你不是很可爱吗！
Oh, Mrs. Puff.
You're pretty cute, too.
哦，帕夫夫人。
你也很可爱啊
[groans]
[呻吟]
See you next week,
Mrs. Puff!
下周见，
泡芙太太！
Amazing.
惊人的。
For once,
这一次，
SpongeBob didn't create
a huge disaster!
海绵宝宝不是创造的
一场巨大的灾难！
Puff!
噗！
Your blasted lighthouse
destroyed the whole town!
你那该死的灯塔
摧毁了整个城镇！
And me restaurant!
还有我的餐厅！
My lighthouse?
我的灯塔？
all: What are you
gonna do about it?
全体：你是什么
会做些什么吗？
[crowd grumbles]
[人群抱怨]
[heavy metal music plays]
[重金属音乐响起]
Talk to the fin!
和鳍说话！